Rockwell Kent
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Art Work, 1910-1972, undated, Series 3:; (Reels 5252, 5741)
  - Artwork by Rockwell Kent, 3.1:
    - Peter Grimes (Reel 5741, Frame 242-323)
      Set Designs, Pencil Drawings and Studies (Act I, Scene II; Act II, Scene I; Act III, Scene II; and undesignated scenes; SKG Estate 2000.3.1-9, 2000.4.1-3), 1968 (oversize).
      Set Designs, Ink and Gouache (Prologue and Act I, Scene I; SKG Estate 2000.8-11), 1968 (oversize).
      Set Design, Ink and Gouache (Act I, Scene II; SKG Estate 2000.5), 1968 (oversize).
      Set Designs, Ink and Gouache (Act II, Scene II; SKG Estate 2000.7, 2000.14.1), 1968 (oversize).
      Set Designs, Ink and Gouache (Act III, Scenes 1 and II; SKG Estate 2000.6, 2000.9), 1968 (oversize).
    - Color Lithograph, Study for War Poster, "Man Killing Nazi Snake" (used in It's Me, O Lord!; SKG Estate 2000.14), circa 1941 (Reel 5741, Frame 324-325)
    - Ink Drawings (Reel 5741, Frame 326-333)
      Detail of Vermont Marble Workers' Strike Poster (used in It's Me, O Lord!; SKG Estate 2000.282), circa 1935.
      Illustration Studies, To Thee (SKG Estate 2000.41), circa 1946.
      Miscellaneous Subjects (SKG Estate 2000.109, 2000.151), undated.
    - Pencil Drawings (Reel 5741, Frame 334-428)
      Design Sketches for Fabrics (one with gouache; SKG Estate 2000.92-93), undated
      Figures SKG Estate 2000.15.2-5, 2000.15.100, 2000.36, 2000.48-52, 2000.78, 2000.88-89, 2000.100-101, 2000.119, 2000.149, 2000.214-215, 2000.301-302, 2000.308, 2000.310-312, 2000.340, 2000.447), undated.
      Figures, circa 1920 (SKG Estate 2000.15.6, 2000.62, 2000.71, 2000.73-74), undated (oversized).
      Figures, Medical Drawings for Schering Corp. (SKG Estate 2000.17.1-2) circa 1942.
      Greenland Subjects (SKG Estate 2000.391, 2000.451-452, 2000.469) undated.
      Illustration Studies, Erewhon (SKG Estate 2000.421), undated.
      Illustration Studies, Greenland Journal (SKG Estate 2000.19-22, 2000.394), undated.
      Illustration Studies, It's Me O Lord! (SKG Estate 2000.300), undated.
      Illustration Studies and Frontispiece, The Saga of Gisli Sour (SKG Estate 2000.436-437), undated.
      Illustration Studies, This Is My Own (SKG Estate 2000.447), 1939.
      Illustrations, Voyaging (SKG Estate 2000.440-443), 1922 (oversize).
      Landscapes (SKG Estate 2000.49, 2000.87, 2000.98-99), undated.
      Landscapes (SKG Estate 2000.57), undated (oversize).
      Miscellaneous Subjects (SKG Estate 2000.77), undated (oversize).
      Miscellaneous Subjects (SKG Estate 2000.36-38, 2000.69, 2000.83, 2000.112, 2000.115, 2000.163, 2000.171, 2000.174, 2000.176-179, 2000.185, 2000.307, 2000.445, 2000.449, 2000.478-479, 2000.497-500), undated.
      Page Designs, Miscellaneous (SKG Estate 2000.82, 2000.84), undated.
      Page Designs, To Thee, centennial history of Rahr Malting Co.], and Rahr Logo (SKG Estate 2000.107, 2000.486, 2000.490), circa 1947.
    - Miscellaneous Media, Paper Stencil Cutout for Dairy Advertisement (SKG Estate 2000.339), circa. 1939 (Reel 5741, Frame 429-430)
  - Artwork by Others, 3.2:
    - Caricature of Kent (by unknown), undated (Reel 5252, Frame 855-856)
    - Various Subjects (Reel 5252, Frame unfilmed)
      (most unidentified and undated, including: drawings and sketches in pencil and ink; colored print; cardboard and wire construction)
    - Artwork by Children (Reel 5252)
      - Drawings by Kent children and others (Reel 5252, Frame unfilmed)
- Printed Matter, 1905-1993, undated, Series 4:; (Reels 5252-5254)
  This series contains publications, articles, and newspaper clippings about Rockwell Kent and his family, items written and/or illustrated by Kent, reviews of his writings and exhibitions, miscellaneous articles on subjects of interest to him and publications inscribed to him. The series also includes printed matter about the Johnstone family, an article by Sally Kent, posters, and maps of the Adirondack region of New York State.
  This series has been partially scanned. Miscellaneous clippings, maps, and monographs by and about Rockwell Kent have not been digitized.
  - About Rockwell Kent, 1916-1972, undated (Reel 5252, Frame 857-1534)
    (includes photo essay on Asgaard house designed by Kent; invitations to meet Rockwell Kent; press clippings)
  - About Rockwell Kent, cont. (Reel 5253, Frame 3-422)
  - Cartoons, 1933, 1948, 1971, undated (Reel 5253, Frame 423-435)
    (satirizing Kent's Greenland trip and artistic style; "Private Lives" informational cartoon; and crossword puzzle including Kent's name)
  - Political Activities, 1932-1933, 1943, 1948, 1953, undated (Reel 5253, Frame 436-551)
    (congressional race materials; Jay Taxpayers Association-R.K., Chairman; Brief for Petitioners in Kent vs. Subversive Activities Control Board; flier written by Kent)
  - Kent Obituaries and Tributes, 1971-1972, undated (Reel 5253, Frame 552-774)
  - Kent Family, 1931, 1969, undated (Reel 5253, Frame 775-792)
  - Writings and Speeches by Kent, 1905, 1925-1962, undated (Reel 5253, Frame 794-957)
  - Articles Illustrated by Rockwell Kent, 1910-1960, undated (Reel 5253, Frame 959-1224)
  - Reproductions of Works by Rockwell Kent, undated (Reel 5253, Frame 1225-1245)
  - Bookplates, undated (Reel 5253, Frame 1246-1265)
    (2 catalogs: "Bookplates by Rockwell Kent" and "Antioch Bookplate Papers, Volume 1")
  - Reviews of Books Written and/or Illustrated by Rockwell Kent (Reel 5253)
    - Wilderness, 1920 (Reel 5253, Frame 1267-1286)
    - Voyaging, 1924-1925 (Reel 5253, Frame 1287-1296)
    - N by E, 1930-1931 (Reel 5253, Frame 1297-1328)
    - Rockwellkentiana, 1933 (Reel 5253, Frame 1329-1332)
    - Salamina, 1936 (Reel 5253, Frame 1333-1348)
    - This Is My Own, 1940-1941 (Reel 5253, Frame 1349-1383)
    - Moby Dick, 1944, 1952 (Reel 5253, Frame 1384-1395)
    - "On the Writings of Rockwell Kent," undated (Reel 5253, Frame 1396-1410)
      (compilation of excerpts of reviews, 1926-1941)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects of Interest to Kent, 1925-1993, undated (Reel 5253, Frame unfilmed)
  - Inscribed to Kent, 1938-1951 (Reel 5253, Frame unfilmed)
  - About Johnstone Family, 1943, 1945 (Reel 5253, Frame 1412-1414)
  - By Sally Kent, 1943, 1961 (Reel 5253, Frame 1416-1446)
  - Posters, (oversize) (Reel 5254, Frame 3-13)
    Twenty-Fourth International Exhibition of Paintings, Carnegie Institute, October 15-December 6, 1925; National Tuberculosis Association, Christmas Seals, 1939; Kent Exhibitions in the USSR, circa 1958-1967 (4 posters, in Russian); Calavenas Divisionistas (not Kent; in Spanish; undated, unfilmed)
  - Maps of New York State, 1993, (oversize) (Reel 5254, Frame unfilmed)
  - Maps of Upstate New York, 1953, 1955, 1966, undated, (7 items) (Reel 5254, Frame unfilmed)
  - Monographs by and about Rockwell Kent (Reel 5254, Frame unfilmed)
    (Johnson, Fridolf, ed. Rockwell Kent: An Anthology of His Works. New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1982; Jones, Dan Burne. The Prints of Rockwell Kent: A Catalogue Raisonn. Chicago and London: University of Chicago Press, 1975; Kent, Rockwell. It's Me, O Lord: The Autobiography of Rockwell Kent. New York: Dodd, Mead & Company, 1955; Kent, Rockwell, ed. World Famous Paintings. New York: Wise & Co., Inc., 1939; Traxel, David. An American Saga: The Life and Times of Rockwell Kent. New York: Harper & Row, Publishers, 1980)
- Miscellaneous Material, 1859-1969, undated, Series 5:; (Reels 5254, 5741)
  This series contains biographical data, legal documents, memorabilia, etc., documenting the life and career of Rockwell Kent. Also, ephemera of unknown origin and relationship are included.
  Biographical data includes membership cards and related membership material from various professional and political organizations; engagement calendars from October 1928 to December 1930; and certificates of initiation and recognition from Joselyn Memorial Museum of Art, Knox College, and Columbia University. Legal documents include Kent's 1924 U.S. passport, and a draft of "Last Will and Testament of Rockwell Kent," dated March 20, 1928.
  Artifacts consist of textile samples, dinnerware, a scarf, and wine cooler designed by Kent or featuring patterns based on his paintings and illustrations. These items are grouped by material type.
  A boxed album of three 33 1/3 rpm long playing records with libretto of Benjamin Britten's opera Peter Grimes, for which Kent created costumes and set designs, was received from the estate of his widow, Sally Kent Gorton, in 2001.
  This series has been partially scanned. Artifacts and audiovisual materials have not been scanned.
  - Biographical Data, 1921, 1943, undated (Reel 5254, Frame 15-80)
  - Legal Documents, 1908, 1924-1928 (Reel 5254, Frame 81-101)
  - Memorabilia, circa 1902-1942 (Reel 5254, Frame 102-183)
  - Artifacts - Fabric samples, Saison "Happily-Married" Fabrics [Bloomcraft, Inc., New York], 1950 (Reel 5254, Frame unfilmed)
    5 pieces: "Pine Tree" (green); "Pine Tree" (cream); "Waves of Grain" (brown); "Deer Season" (green); "Deer Season" (orange)
  - Artifacts - Fabric samples, "Waverly Prints," undated (Reel 5254, Frame unfilmed)
    2 pieces: trees, mountains, and figures in historical costume (tan); trees, mountains, and figures in historical costume (green)
  - Artifacts - Moby Dick silk scarf, printed for the American Artists Group, New York, 1940s (Reel 5254, Frame unfilmed)
    38 in. ?? 38 in., two shades of brown with white (worn and rehemmed in places)
  - Artifacts - Ceramics - Vernon Kilns dinnerware (Reel 5254, Frame unfilmed)
    6 pieces Moby Dick pattern: 10 in. plate, 7 in. plate, cup with saucer, demitasse cup with saucer; 9 pieces Salamina pattern: 10 in. plate, 8 in plate, 6 in. plate, egg cup, bowl, cup with saucer, demitasse cup with saucer; 9 pieces Our America pattern: 10 in. plate, 9 in. plate, 8 in. plate, 7 in. plate, 6 in. plate, sauce dish, bowl, demitasse cup with saucer
  - Artifacts - Ceramics - Rubber stamp with ceramic handle and base (Reel 5254, Frame unfilmed)
    stamp image includes the words "Air Mail" and drawing of a bird flying over water and mountains; ceramic handle in the form of a bird perched on a tree stump
  - Metal - wine cooler produced by Chase Brass & Copper Co., Incorporated, Waterbury, Conn., 1934 (Reel 5254, Frame unfilmed)
    chrome-plated bucket, 9 1/4 in. tall, 8 1/4 in. circumference at top, with reproduction of Kent's woodcut Bacchus
  - Miscellaneous (Reel 5254)
    - "Facsimile Letter from John Brown to the Rev. Luther Humphery, 19th November 1859" (Reel 5254, Frame 185-191)
    - "Phrenological Character of Mrs. C. A. Holgate [grandmother?] Given at Fowler & Wells' Phrenological Cabinet, June 5, 1867, by Nelson Sizer, Practical Phrenologist" (Reel 5254, Frame 192-203)
    - Petty cash book of George Rockwell Kent, [father of Rockwell Kent], undated (Reel 5254, Frame 204-234)
    - "Notes on Roofing" by Rockwell Kent, circa 1912 (Reel 5254, Frame 235-237)
    - Technical Information, 1934-1952, undated (Reel 5254, Frame 238-261)
      (notes and instructions for preparation of grounds and pigments)
    - Notes on Art, undated (Reel 5254, Frame 262-315)
      (from various sources, in unknown hand; includes bibliographic citations)
    - Lists of Supplies and Provisions for Expeditions, undated (Reel 5254, Frame 316-323)
    - Map of Unidentified Place Drawn by Rockwell Kent, undated (Reel 5254, Frame 324-326)
    - Music Manuscripts and Lyrics (in unidentified language(s)), undated (Reel 5254, Frame 327-342)
    - Architectural Drawing (oversize), Residence for Mr. & Mrs. Rockwell Kent, AuSable Forks, New York, Jeremiah Oosterbaan, Architect, 1969 (Reel 5254, Frame 343-347)
  - Motion Picture Film of [Kent in Greenland], transferred to videotape, undated (Reel unfilmed)
  - Sound Recordings of Peter Grimes by Benjamin Britten, (oversized boxed album of three 33 1/3 rpm long playing records) (Reel unfilmed)
  - Libretto from Sound Recordings of Peter Grimes by Benjamin Britten (SKG Estate 2000.1) (Reel unfilmed)
- Photographs, circa 1840-1970, undated, Series 6:; (Reels 5254-5255, 5741)
  Photographs, mainly unannotated, are of people, miscellaneous subjects, places, and works of art. Additional photographs were received from the estate of Kent's widow, Sally Kent Gorton, in 2001 and were microfilmed at a later date on reel 5741. Among them are photographs of people including Kent and his wives, Ted R. Lambert and Eugene Vuchatic; also, views of Asgaard Farm, the rebuilt Kent house at AuSable Forks, N.Y., and Kent's grave.
  The photographs are organized into subseries and arranged in rough chronological order:
  6.1: People, 1840-1970, undated
  6.2: Miscellaneous Subjects, 1920s-1960s, undated
  6.3: Places, A-Z, 1904-1960s, undated
  6.4: Works of Art, 1902-1962, undated
  6.5: Duplicates Prints, Negatives, and Color Transparencies, undated
  The bulk of this series has been digitized. Some photographs of Kent ancestors, duplicate prints, negatives and transparencies have not been scanned.
  - People, 1840-1970, undated, 6.1:
    - Family, circa 1840-early 20th century, 1950s-1960s (Reel 5254, Frame unfilmed)
      (daguerreotypes and ambrotypes of Kent ancestors)
    - Family, Photographic Prints (Reel 5254, Frame 349-385)
      (depicting various family members, including Rockwell Kent as a young boy, and photograph albums)
    - Kent Family Album Vol. 1, undated (Reel 5254, Frame 386-402)
    - Kent Family Album Vol. 2, late 1800s (Reel 5254, Frame 403-424)
    - Kent Family Album Vol. 3, early 1900s (Reel 5254, Frame 425-476)
    - Kent Family Album Vol. 4, circa 1885-circa 1915 (Reel 5254, Frame 477-483)
    - Kent Family Album Vol. 5, undated (Reel 5254, Frame 484-536)
    - Kent Family, 1950s-1960s (Reel 5254, Frame 564-577)
    - Rockwell Kent, 1885-1970 (Reel 5254, Frame 578-878)
      (includes Rockwell Kent family dressed in animal skins, circa 1915; at Sam Barlow's, 1920s; portraits by Arnold Genthe and Carl Van Vechten, 1920s-1930s; at a camp for teenagers, 1950s; at work painting, 1930s-1960s; at new house, 1970)
    - Rockwell Kent, 1920s-1960s (Reel 5741, Frame 436-449)
    - Rockwell Kent, 1940s, (oversize) (Reel 5741, Frame 431-433)
    - Rockwell Kent with Others, circa 1930s (Reel 5741, Frame 450-452)
    - Rockwell Kent with others, 1910s-1970 (Reel 5254, Frame 879-1012)
    - Rockwell Kent in Alaska, 1918-1919 (Reel 5254, Frame 1013-1017)
      (includes Kent's son, Rockwell Kent III)
    - Rockwell Kent in Greenland, 1930s (Reel 5254, Frame 1018-1037)
      (includes photo album, disbound and kept in original order)
    - Rockwell Kent in Moscow, 1960 (Reel 5254, Frame 1038-1043)
    - Rockwell Kent in Moscow, 1968 (Reel 5741, Frame 453-455)
    - Rockwell Kent in Tierra del Fuego, South America, 1922 (Reel 5254, Frame 1044-1051)
    - Kathleen Kent (first wife), 1890s-1910 (Reel 5254, Frame 1052-1058)
    - Kathleen Kent (first wife), circa 1905 (Reel 5741, Frame 456-457)
    - Kent Child [Kathleen?], circa 1912 (Reel 5741, Frame 458-459)
    - Kent children, 1910s-1920s, undated (Reel 5254, Frame 1059-1111)
      (some with their mother, Kathleen)
    - Frances Kent (second wife), circa 1930 (Reel 5254, Frame 1112-1129)
    - Frances Kent (second wife), 1930s (Reel 5741, Frame 460-462)
    - Rockwell and Frances Kent, 1930s (Reel 5741, Frame 463)
    - Rockwell and Frances Kent, 1930s (Reel 5254, Frame 1136-1140)
    - Family at Kent House, AuSable, N.Y., 1930s (Reel 5254, Frame 1130-1135)
      (includes Kent, Kent children, and Frances)
    - Sally Kent (third wife), 1940s-1960s (Reel 5254, Frame 1141-1178)
    - Sally Kent (third wife), circa 1950 (Reel 5741, Frame 464-465)
    - Sally Kent with others, 1940s (Reel 5741, Frame 466-470)
    - Rockwell and Sally Kent, 1952 (Reel 5741, Frame 471-473)
    - Rockwell and Sally Kent, 1940s-1970 (Reel 5254, Frame 1179-1206)
    - Rockwell and Sally Kent in Chicago, 1960 (Reel 5254, Frame 1207-1224)
      (Kent woodcut (?) and newspaper articles, one disbound album and one disbound scrapbook containing photos)
    - Rockwell and Sally Kent in the USSR, 1962, 1964, 1967, undated (Reel 5254, Frame 1225-1443)
      (includes disbound pages from albums and one album (vol. 5), undated)
    - Rockwell and Sally Kent in the USSR, cont. (Reel 5255, Frame 3-293)
    - Grandchildren, [circa 1960s-1970], undated (Reel 5255, Frame 294-302)
      (children of Rockwell Kent III; Kathleen Finney, undated; Clara Kent; Susan or Natsha (Tasha) Kent; Tasha Kent and daughter; unidentified)
    - Alastair Johnstone (relative of Sally Kent), 1940s (Reel 5255, Frame 303-307)
    - William Merritt Chase Summer School, Shinnecock, Long Island, circa 1900-1902 (Reel 5255, Frame 308-311)
      (includes interior view of Kent's studio)
    - Events, various dates (Reel 5255, Frame 313-339)
    - Events, 1960s (Reel 5741, Frame 474-478)
    - Eugene Vuchetich working on a bust of Kent, circa 1960 (Reel 5741, Frame 480-482)
    - Soviet Art Jury, [1960s?] (Reel 5255, Frame 340-346)
    - Marsden Hartley, 1913 (Reel 5255, Frame 347-351)
      (wearing costume, inscribed: "This is yours humbly--after the Dirty Arts Ball 7 a.m., Marsden Hartley, Paris, June 1913")
    - Ted R. Lambert, Signal Corps Dog Derby, 1933 (Reel 5741, Frame 479)
    - Paul Robeson, 1950s (Reel 5255, Frame 352-363)
    - Pete Seeger (most photos also include Sally Kent), 1960s (Reel 5255, Frame 364-369)
    - Other Friends (most unidentified), 1910s-1960s (Reel 5255, Frame 370-461)
      (includes photographic prints of Soviet students' visit to Kent's home in AuSable Forks, N.Y., 1942)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects, 1920s-1960s, undated, 6.2:
    - Scenes from Maxwell Anderson's play, The Eve of St. Mark, undated (Reel 5255, Frame 463-471)
    - Arctic Art (Reel 5255, Frame 472-479)
    - Direction [sailboat], 1920s-1960s (Reel 5255, Frame 480-508)
    - Boats (Reel 5255, Frame 509-513)
    - John Brown's grave, Lake Placid, N.Y. (Reel 5255, Frame 514-520)
    - Miriam Brenner Grubin's grave (Reel 5255, Frame 521-523)
    - Rockwell Kent's grave, 1977 (Reel 5741, Frame 484-486)
    - "Candidates for RK's hand and bed," by Frances Kent and Bob Benchley, undated (Reel 5255, Frame 525-537)
    - Rebuilt House, AuSable Forks, N.Y., 1977 (Reel 5741, Frame 487)
    - Houses (Reel 5255, Frame 538-617)
      (includes Kent's original and rebuilt homes and his studio at AuSable Forks, N.Y.; unidentified buildings; also Kent's mother's house in Tarrytown, N.Y., and son Gordon's house in Cazenovia, N.Y.)
    - Whales and Whaling (Reel 5255, Frame 618-669)
      (research material for Moby Dick illustrations)
    - Miscellaneous (Reel 5255, Frame 670-680)
      (includes animals, "Adolf Loves Lindy" billboard; Miners at Inland Steel Company; Roosevelt theater marquee ("If War Comes Tomorrow, now showing"); and unidentified city plaza [possibly San Francisco])
  - Places, A - Z, 1904-1960s, undated, 6.3:
    - Alaska, 1918-1919 (Reel 5255, Frame 681-713)
    - Asgaard Farm, AuSable Forks, N.Y., 1930s-1960s, undated (Reel 5255, Frame 714-753)
    - Asgaard Farm, AuSable Forks, N.Y., 1930s-1940s (Reel 5741, Frame 488-489)
    - AuSable Forks, N.Y., and vicinity, early 20th century-1960s (Reel 5255, Frame 754-789)
    - Canadian Rockies, 1950s-1960s (Reel 5255, Frame 790-808)
    - Faroe Islands, undated (Reel 5255, Frame 809-814)
    - France, 1919, undated (Reel 5255, Frame 815-824)
    - Greenland, 1930s (Reel 5255, Frame 825-994)
    - Greenland and Denmark, 1930s (Reel 5255, Frame 995-1026)
    - Ireland, 1926 (Reel 5255, Frame 1027-1041)
    - Monhegan Island, Maine, 1904-1926, 1950s, undated (Reel 5255, Frame 1042-1120)
    - New York, N.Y., 1910s-1920s (Reel 5255, Frame 1121-1128)
    - Newfoundland, circa 1914-1915 (Reel 5255, Frame 1129-1134)
    - Puerto Rico, 1937 (Reel 5255, Frame 1135-1151)
    - Tierra del Fuego, South America, 1922, undated (Reel 5254, Frame 537-563)
      (disbound albums and one album (vol. 6) [Tierra del Fuego? (circa 1922)] and Monhegan, including some photographs of Rockwell Kent, undated)
    - Tierra del Fuego, South America, cont. (Reel 5255, Frame 1152-1349)
    - USSR, undated (Reel 5255, Frame 1350-1397)
    - Winona, Minn., circa 1912-1913 (Reel 5255, Frame 1398-1413)
    - Unidentified places (Reel 5255, Frame 1414-1453)
      (probably of Tierra del Fuego and Greenland)
  - Works of Art, 1909-1962, undated, 6.4:
    Works of art found here are primarily by Kent but there are alos portraits of Rockwell Kent and miscellaneous works of ar and art objects by unknown artists at the end of the subseries.
    - China designs for Vernon Kilns, circa 1938-1943 (Reel 5255, Frame 1456-1461)
    - Drawings, 1920-1962, undated (Reel 5255, Frame 1462-1501)
      (includes undated self-portrait)
    - Lettering, undated (Reel 5255, Frame 1502-1503)
    - Lithographs, undated (Reel 5255, Frame 1504-1512)
    - Medals, 1938, undated (Reel 5255, Frame 1513-1518)
    - General Electric Co., New York World's Fair, Mural, 1939 (Reel 5255, Frame 1519-1528)
      (some views include Kent)
    - On Earth Peace Mural (Reel 5255, Frame 1529-1535)
    - Post Office Department, Washington, D.C. Mural, 1937 (Reel 5255, Frame 1536-1544)
    - Adirondacks, undated (Reel 5255, Frame 1545-1554)
    - Paintings-Landscapes, Alaska, 1919 (Reel 5255, Frame 1555-1582)
    - Paintings-Landscapes, Mt. Assiniboine, undated (Reel 5255, Frame 1583-1586)
    - Paintings-Landscapes, Berkshire, Mass., 1909, undated (Reel 5255, Frame 1587-1590)
    - Paintings-Landscapes, France, undated (Reel 5255, Frame 1591-1599)
    - Paintings-Landscapes, Greenland, 1930s (Reel 5255, Frame 1600-1641)
    - Paintings-Landscapes, Ireland, 1926 (Reel 5255, Frame 1642-1665)
    - Paintings-Landscapes, Monhegan Island, Maine, 1907 (Reel 5255, Frame 1666-1694)
    - Paintings-Landscapes, Newfoundland, 1914-1915 (Reel 5255, Frame 1695-1715)
    - Paintings-Landscapes, New Hampshire, undated (Reel 5255, Frame 1716-1721)
    - Paintings-Landscapes, Steinway Collection, 1928, undated (Reel 5255, Frame 1722-1728)
    - Paintings-Landscapes, Tierra del Fuego, circa 1922 (Reel 5255, Frame 1729-1747)
    - Paintings-Landscapes, Vermont, 1919-1925 (Reel 5255, Frame 1748-1768)
    - Paintings-Miscellaneous Figures and Still Life, undated (Reel 5255, Frame 1769-1781)
    - Watercolors, undated (Reel 5255, Frame 1782-1794)
    - Exhibition Installations, Various Locations, 1930-1949 (Reel 5255, Frame 1795-1837)
    - Exhibition Installations, USSR, 1958 (Reel 5255, Frame 1838-1846)
    - Portraits of Rockwell Kent, 1928, 1931, 1962, undated (Reel 5255, Frame 1847-1854)
      (by F. G. Mories, Victoria Ebbels Hutson, Ernest Hamlin Baker, and unidentified artist name written in Russian)
    - Works of Art and Miscellaneous Objects by Unknown Artists, undated (Reel 5255, Frame unfilmed)
  - Duplicate Prints, Negatives and Color Transparencies, undated, 6.5:
    - Duplicates, Rockwell Kent (Reel 5255, Frame unfilmed)
    - Duplicates, Sally Kent; Francis Kent, R.K.'s mother (?) (Reel 5255, Frame unfilmed)
    - Duplicates, Kathleen Finney (granddaughter) (Reel 5255, Frame unfilmed)
    - Duplicates, Rockwell and Sally Kent, and friends (Reel 5255, Frame unfilmed)
    - Duplicates, Asgaard Farm (Reel 5255, Frame unfilmed)
    - Duplicates, Works of Art by Kent (Reel 5255, Frame unfilmed)
    - Negatives, People (Reel 5255, Frame unfilmed)
    - Negatives, Works of Art by Kent (Reel 5255, Frame unfilmed)
    - Negatives, Works of Art by Others (Reel 5255, Frame unfilmed)
    - Color Transparencies, Works of Art by Kent (Reel 5255, Frame unfilmed)